Because Flask is a Python library,
因为 Flask 是一个 Python 库
you can use any other Python library in a Flask app.
你可以在 Flask 应用中使用任何其他的 Python 库
This makes Flask a great choice for data science because you can use
这使得 Flask 成为数据科学的绝佳选择 因为你可以在
data science tools like Pandas or NumPy inside your Flask app.
Flask 应用中使用数据科学工具 如 Pandas 或 NumPy
Here's an example; I've gone to the World Bank website and downloaded data
举个例子 我去世界银行网站并下载了数据
about rural population percentages for various countries over the past 50 years or so.
数据是关于过去 50 年左右各国的农村人口比例
I downloaded the data as a CSV file,
将数据下载为 CSV 文件
clicking down here and then I uploaded the CSV file into the workspace.
点击下面这里 然后将 CSV 文件上传到 workspace
I created this data folder,
我创建了这个 data 文件夹
and then I uploaded it here.
然后上传到这里
If you haven't uploaded anything to the workspace before,
如果你之前没有向 workspace 上传过文件
you just click on this plus sign and then you can create new files,
只需点击这个加号 然后就可以创建新文件、
new folders or upload a file or upload a folder.
创建新文件夹或上传文件、上传文件夹
Looking at the data, you can see that it's
查看数据 可以看到数据不太干净
not quite clean and it needs some data wrangling,
需要进行一些数据整理
you can do this wrangling directly in your routes.py file.
你可以直接在 routes.py 文件中进行这些整理
You just need to import any libraries you're going to use like the Pandas library,
只需要导入你要使用的库 如 Pandas
so I'm going to do that.
这正是我要做的
Then, I'm going to copy and paste some code I wrote to wrangle the dataset,
然后 复制粘贴我编写的一些整理数据集的代码
and get the data into a form that Plotly will be able to use.
并将数据转换为 Plotly 能够使用的形式
I'll paste this code below the video as well so that you can study it in more detail.
我会将此代码粘贴到视频下方 方便你能更详细地研究
But essentially, all it does is filter out the dataset for
不过实际上 代码所做的只是筛选一些特定的国家
certain countries and get the data for just 1990 and 2015.
获得 1990 年和 2015 年的数据
Starting up the app,
启动应用
you'll see that everything still works fine,
你会发现一切仍然正常
and in fact I added a couple of print statements into
实际上 我在代码中添加了几个打印语句
my code so that you could see the results of my data wrangling.
方便你看到我的数据整理结果
However, now my routes.py file looks a bit messy,
但是现在我的 routes.py 文件看起来有点乱
so I'm going to refactor this code so that everything's a bit cleaner.
我要重构代码 使其更加整洁
I'm going to create a new folder and call it
创建一个新文件夹 称其为 wrangling_scripts
wrangling scripts and then inside this folder,
然后在这个文件夹中
I'm going to create a new file and call it wrangling.py.
我要创建一个新文件并将其命名为 wrangling.py
Okay, and then wrangling.py,
现在就是填充 wrangling.py
I'm just going to take all of
我只需要拿走所有的数据整理代码
this data wrangling code and cut it out of routes and put it in wrangling.py.
将其从 routes 中剪切并放入 wrangling.py 中
Now, I need to import Pandas and then I'm going to make all of this into
现在 我需要导入 Pandas 然后把所有这些都放入一个函数中
a function and the return for this function is just going to be this data variable.
该函数的返回值就是这个 data 变量
Okay. Now returning to routes.py and looking at the workspace folders,
好的 现在返回 routes.py 查看 workspace 文件夹
I'm going to say from wrangling scripts.wrangling,
编写 from wrangling_scripts.wrangling
and then import this data wrangling function.
导入这个 data_wrangling 函数
Then, I'm going to call this function and save the results in
然后 调用此函数并保存结果到 data 变量
the data variable and then just print out the results so we can see it.
然后打印出结果以便观察
Now, I'm going to start the app up,
现在 我要启动应用
okay and you can see everything's still working except now the
好的 你可以看到一切仍然有效
routes.py file stays clean and it's easier to understand what's going on.
只是现在的 routes.py 文件更整洁 更容易理解了
Now, of course you might want to do some of
当然 你可能想要在
this wrangling outside of your web app and then upload a cleaner CSV file,
Web 应用之外做好数据整理的工作 然后上传更干净的 CSV 文件
but you'd still need a way to load the CSV file which you can do with Pandas.
但是你仍然需要一种方法来加载 CSV 文件 Pandas 就可以完成
In the next part of the lesson,
在本课程的下一部分
we're going to add Plotly so that we can
我们将添加 Plotly
actually render this data as a data visualization.
将此数据真正呈现为数据可视化